Has Prudential Denied you Long Term Disability Insurance Claim?
Hi, I'm Marc Whitehead a Board Certified Insurance Lawyer
The Prudential Insurance Company of America
is a global company with over 135 years in the insurance business
The Prudential Insurance Company is the Second largest provider
of group life insurance in the US.
and a leading carrier of Short Term and Long Term Insurance
Prudential's Long Term Disability coverage often takes over
short term disability policies end
Replacing part of the policy holders salary if they become disabled
for a long period of time
The employer may pay part of this group insurance policy
or they may share the cost with the employee
Because these are group policies
Most lawsuits that are filed to appeal Prudential's Claims denials
are filed Employee Retirement Insurance Security Act
or better known as ERISA.
If the Companies unfairly rejected your claim
or discontinued your benefits. They are aware that if
the court overturns their denial and makes them pay, in most
cases there's not punishment under ERISA statutes.
They would only have to pay what they would
have owed you in the first place.
There have been many cases recently alleging Prudential's
denial of disability benefits were unfair, bias or unreasonable
Some examples include
a Policy holder that was approved by Prudential to receive
Long Term disability payments but after 24 months
Prudential reviewed the plaintiffs eligibility and determined
that the plaintiff no longer satisfied the definition of disability
of disability under the language. However the plaintiff was deemed
disabled by the Social Security Administration
using the same medical records submitted to Prudential
In another Lawsuit against Prudential for Long Term Disability Denials
Prudential acted as both the payer of the insurance claim and
and the claims administrator for the plan
When Prudential denied the claim for Long Term Disability
the plaintiff alleged that Prudential acted in a conflict of interest by
the fiduciary, the insurance provider and the claims administrator
its critical to hire disability claims lawyer who has the resources
experience to demonstrate to the court that you are in fact disabled
under the terms of the policy
If Prudential has wrongfully denied you of your disability payments
Our Attorneys can help you fight back
We're a National Disability Law Firm with significant experience
representing Prudential Claim
This Topic is discussed more in my free ebook:
Lon Term Disability insurance policies: How to Unravel the Mystery and Prove your Claim
Visit www.disabilitydenials.com for a free downloadable copy
Or call 1-800-562-9830 to discuss your particular disability insurance issue.
I'm Marc Whitehead, thanks for watching!